Thanks for watching!
There's an old joke.
two elderly women are at a Catskill Mountain resort
and one of them says,
boy, the food at this place is really terrible.
The other one says, yeah, I know, and such small portions.
Well, that's essentially how I feel about life,
full of loneliness and misery and suffering and unhappiness,
and it's all over much too quickly.
The other important joke for me
is one that's usually attributed to Groucho Marx,
but I think it appears originally in Freud's wit
and its relation to the unconscious.
And it goes like this, I'm paraphrasing.
I would never want to belong to any club
that would have someone like me for a member.
That's the key joke of my adult life
in terms of my relationships with women.
You know, lately the strangest things
have been going through my mind because I turned 40
and I guess I'm going through a life crisis or something.
I don't know.
And I'm not worried about aging.
I'm not one of those characters.
Although I'm balding slightly on top.
That's about the worst you can say about me.
I think I'm going to get better as I get older.
You know, I think I'm going to be the balding, virile type, you know, as opposed to, say, the distinguished gray, for instance, you know.
Unless I'm neither of those two.
Unless I'm one of those guys with saliva dribbling out of his mouth who wanders into a cafeteria with a shopping bag screaming about socialism.
Annie and I broke up, and I still can't get my mind around that.
You know, I keep sifting the pieces of the relationship through my mind and examining my life and trying to figure out where did the screw-up come, you know.
and a year ago we were in love, you know, and I just...
And it's funny, I'm not a morose type.
I'm not a depressive character.
I, you know, I was a reasonably happy kid, I guess.
I was brought up in Brooklyn during World War II.
He's been depressed.
All of a sudden he can't do anything.
Why are you depressed, Alvy?
Tell Dr. Flicker.
It's something he read.
Something he read, huh?
The universe is expanding.
The universe is expanding?
Well, the universe is everything.
And if it's expanding, someday it will break apart
and that will be the end of everything.
What is that your business?
He stopped doing his homework.
What's the point?
What has the universe got to do with it?
You're here in Brooklyn.
Brooklyn is not expanding.
It won't be expanding for billions of years yet, Albie.
We've got to try and enjoy ourselves while we're here, huh?
Huh?
My analyst says I exaggerate my childhood memories,
but I swear I was brought up underneath the roller coaster
in the Coney Island section of Brooklyn.
Maybe that accounts for my personality,
which is a little nervous, I think.
You know, I have a hyperactive imagination.
My mind tends to jump around a little,
and I have some trouble between fantasy and reality.
My father ran the bumper car concession.
There he is, and there I am.
I used to get my aggression out through those cars all the time.
I remember the staff at our public school.
You know, we had a saying that those who can't do, teach,
and those who can't teach, teach Jim.
And, of course, those who couldn't do anything, I think,
were assigned to our school.
I must say, I always thought my schoolmates were idiots.
Melvin Greenglass, you know, his fat little face,
and Henrietta Farrell, just Miss Perfect all the time,
and Ivan Ackerman.
Always the wrong answer. Always.
Seven-three is lying.
Even then, I knew they were just jerks.
In 1942, I had already discovered women.
No, he kissed me! He kissed me!
That's the second time this month.
Step up here.
What did I do?
You should be ashamed of yourself.
Why? I was just expressing a healthy sexual curiosity.
Six-year-old boys don't have girls on their minds.
I did.
For God's sake, Sally,
never before speaks of a latency period.
Well, I never had a latency period.
I can't help it.
Why couldn't you have been more like Donald?
Now there was a model boy.
Tell the folks where you are today, Donald.
I run a profitable dress company.
Boy, sometimes I wonder where my classmates are today.
I'm president of the pinkest plumbing company.
I sell tallies.
I used to be a heroin addict.
Now I'm a methadone addict.
I'm into leather.
I lost track of most of my old schoolmates,
but I wound up a comedian.
They did not take me in the army. I was, interestingly enough, I was 4P.
Yes. In the event of war, I'm a hostage.
You always only saw the worst in people.
You never could get along with anyone in school.
You were always out of step with the world.
Even when you got famous, you still distrusted the world.
I distinctly heard it. He muttered under his breath, Jew.
You're crazy.
No, I'm not. We were walking off the tennis court,
and, you know, he was there and me and his wife,
and he looked at her and then they both looked at me,
and under his breath he said, Jew.
Alva, you're a total paranoid.
How am I a paranoid? I pick up on those kind of things.
You know, I was having lunch with some guys from NBC,
so I said, uh, did you eat yet or what?
And Tom Christie said, no, Jew.
Not did you. Jew eat? Jew?
No, not did you eat, but Jew eat? Jew?
You get it? Jew eat?
Uh, Max, you, uh...
You're calling me Max.
Why, Max? It's a good name for you.
Max, you see conspiracies in everything.
No, I don't. You know, I was in a record store.
Listen to this.
So I know there's this big, tall, blonde, crew-cutted guy,
and he's looking at me in a funny way and smiling,
and he's saying, yes, we have a sale this week on Wagner.
Wagner, Max. Wagner.
So I know what he's really trying to tell me very significantly.
Wagner.
Right, Max.
California, Max.
Just forget the hell out of this crazy city.
Forget it, Max.
We moved to sunny L.A. All of show business is out there, Max.
No, I cannot. You keep bringing it up,
but I don't want to live in a city where the only cultural advantage
is that you can make a right turn on a red light.
All right, Max, forget it.
Aren't you going to be late for meeting Annie?
I'm going to meet her in Father Beekman.
I think I have a few minutes left, right?
Are you on television?
No.
You know, once in a while, you know, I occasionally...
What's your name?
You wouldn't know it. It doesn't matter. What's the difference?
You're on, uh, the, uh, the Johnny Carson, right?
Once in a while, you know, I'm, you know, every now and then...
What's your name?
I'm, uh, I'm Robert Redford.
Come on!
Alfie Singer.
It was nice.
Thanks very much for everything.
Hey!
What?
This is Alfie Singer.
Fellas, you know...
This guy's on television.
Alfie Singer, right?
Am I right?
Give me a break.
This guy's on television.
I need the large polo mallet.
Who's on television?
This guy on a Johnny Carson show.
Fellas, what is this?
A meeting of the Teamsters?
What program?
Can I have your autograph?
You don't want my autograph.
No, I do.
It's for my girlfriend.
Make it out to Ralph.
Your girlfriend's name is Ralph?
It's for my brother.
I'll be singer!
Really, I'll be singing at Disney?
This is I'll be singer!
I'll be singer over here!
It's all right, fellas.
Jesus, what'd you do?
Come by way of the Panama Canal?
I'm in a bad mood, OK?
Bad mood?
I'm standing with the cast of The Godfather.
You're going to have to learn to deal with it.
Deal?
I'm dealing with two guys named Cheech.
Okay, please. I have a headache, all right?
You are in a bad mood. You must be getting your period.
I'm not getting my period. Jesus.
Every time anything out of the ordinary happens, you think that I'm getting my period.
A little latter. I think one of them may have missed it.
Has the picture started yet?
It started two minutes ago.
That's it. Forget it. I can't go in.
Two minutes, Albie.
No, I'm sorry. I can't do it. We've blown it already.
You know, I can't go in in the middle.
In the middle? We only missed the titles. They're in Swedish.
You want to get coffee for two hours or something?
Two hours? No, I'm going in.
Go ahead. Goodbye.
While we're talking, we could be inside. You know that?
Hey, can we not stand here and argue in front of everybody?
All right.
Because I get embarrassed.
All right, all right. So what do you want to do?
I don't know now. You want to go to another movie?
Let's go see The Sorrow and the Pity.
Oh, come on. We've seen it.
I'm not in the mood to see a four-hour documentary on Nazis.
Well, I'm sorry. I can't.
I've got to see a picture exactly from the start to the finish.
Because I'm anal.
That's a polite word for what you are.
We saw the Fellini film last Tuesday.
It is not one of his best.
He likes a cohesive structure.
You get the feeling that he's not absolutely sure what it is he wants to say.
Of course, I've always felt he was essentially a technical filmmaker.
Granted, L'Estrada was a great film.
Great in its use of negative imagery more than anything else.
But that central cohesive core...
You know, that must lead to an artist's work,
leading from one to the other.
He's screaming his opinions in my ear.
You know what I'm talking about?
Like all that Juliet of the Spirits or Satyricon.
I found it incredibly indulgent.
You know, he really is.
He's one of the most indulgent filmmakers.
He really is.
And without getting...
Let's put it this way.
What are you depressed about?
I miss my therapy. I overslept.
What can you possibly oversleep?
The alarm clock.
Do you know what a hostile gesture that is to me?
I know, because of our sexual problem, right?
Everybody online at the New Yorker
has to know our rate of intercourse.
It's like Samuel Beckett.
I admire the technique, but it doesn't hit me on a gut level.
I'd like to hit this guy on a gut level.
Stop it, Albie.
He's spitting on my neck.
The most important thing of all is a community of vision.
And you know something else?
You're so egocentric that if I miss my therapy,
you can only think of it in terms of how it affects you.
Weltanschauung is what it is.
It's probably on their first date, right?
It's a worldview.
Probably met by answering an ad in the New York Review of Books.
30-ish academic wishes to meet woman who's interested in Mozart, James Joyce, and sodomy.
What do you mean, our sexual problem?
I mean, I'm comparatively normal for a guy raised in Brooklyn.
Okay, I'm very sorry.
My sexual problem.
Okay, my sexual problem, huh?
I never read that.
That was Henry James, right?
Novel?
The sequel to Turn of the Screw?
It's the influence of television.
Now, Marshall McLuhan deals with it in terms of it being a high intensity, you understand?
A hot medium.
What I wouldn't give for a large sock with horse manure in it.
What do you do when you get stuck on a movie line with a guy like this behind you?
Wait a minute, why can't I give my opinion?
It's a free country.
He can give you.
You have to give it so loud.
I mean, aren't you ashamed to pontificate like that?
And the funny part of it is, Marshall McLuhan, you don't know anything about Marshall McLuhan's
work.
I happen to teach a class at Columbia called TV, Media, and Culture.
So I think that my insights into Mr. McLuhan will have a great deal of validity.
Oh, do you?
Well, that's funny because I happen to have Mr. McLuhan right here.
So, yeah, just let me, come over here a second.
Tell him.
I heard what you were saying.
You know nothing of my work.
You mean my whole fallacy is wrong.
How you ever got to teach a course in anything is totally amazing.
Boy, if life were only like this.
June 14, 1940.
The German army occupies Paris.
All over the country, people are desperate for every available scrap of news.
Boy, those guys in the French Resistance are really brave, you know?
They have to listen to Maurice Chevalier sing so much.
I know. Sometimes I ask myself how I'd stand up under torture.
You? You're kidding.
The Gestapo would take away your Bloomingdale's charge card and you'd tell them everything.
That movie makes me feel guilty.
Yeah, because it's supposed to.
I mean, uh...
What's the matter?
I don't...
It's not natural.
We're sleeping in a bed together.
You know, it's been a long time.
Well, it's just that, you know, I mean,
I got to sing tomorrow night, so I have to rest my voice.
It's only some kind of an excuse.
You used to think that I was very sexy.
When we first started going out, we had sex constantly.
We're probably listed in the Guinness Book of World Records.
world records. Well, Albie, it'll pass. It'll pass. It's just that I'm going through a phase,
that's all. I mean, you've been married before. You know how things can get.
You were very hot for Allison at first.
And you know that you're on right after Chris Brown, which looks about 20 minutes,
something like that. Excuse me, when do I go on? Who are you?
Albie Singer. I'm the comedian. Oh, comedian.
Yeah.
Oh, uh, you're on next?
What do you mean next?
I mean you're on right after this act.
No, it can't be because he's a comic.
Yes.
So what are you telling me?
You're putting on two comics in a row?
Why not?
No, I'm sorry.
I'm not gonna, I can't, I don't wanna go on after another comedian.
It's okay.
No, because they're, they're laughing, so I, I, I'd rather not.
If you don't mind, I prefer...
Will you relax, please?
They're gonna love you, I know.
I prefer not to because, look, they're laughing at him, see?
So what are you telling me that I've got he's gonna laugh at him for a couple of minutes and I gotta go out there
I gotta get laughs through how much can they laugh? They're there laugh that
Do you feel alright?
Yeah, how's your name? Porchnik
A group from the NAACP.
Nice.
Mm-hmm.
And he said, boys, never worry.
He said, they bring the best...
So, uh, what are you telling me?
You work for Stevenson all the time, or what?
No, no, no, I'm, uh, I'm in the midst of doing my thesis.
On what?
A political commitment in 20th century literature.
You're like New York Jewish left-wing liberal intellectual,
Central Park West, Brandeis University,
the socialist summer camps,
and the father with the Ben Shahn drawings, right?
and they're really, you know, strike-oriented, kind of...
Stop me before I make a complete imbecile of myself.
No, that was wonderful.
I love being reduced to a cultural stereotype.
Right, I'm a bigot, you know, but for the left.
Thank you.
I have to go out there.
Say something encouraging, quickly.
I think you're cute.
Thank you.
Go ahead.
I don't know why they would have me at this kind of rally, because, excuse me, I'm not
essentially a political comedian at all.
I interestingly had dated a woman in the Eisenhower administration briefly, and it was ironic
to me because um because i was trying to do to her what eisenhower has been doing to the country
for the last eight years i'm sorry i can't go through with this because i can't get it off my
mind allison it's obsessing me oh i'm getting tired of it i need your attention but it doesn't
make any sense he drove past the book depository and the police said conclusively that it was an
So how is it possible for Oswald to have fired from two angles at once?
It doesn't make sense.
Howdy.
I'll tell you this.
He was not marksman enough to hit a moving target at that range.
But if there was a second assassin, that's it.
We've been through this.
They recovered the shells from that rifle.
All right.
Now, what are you saying now?
Everybody on the Warren Commission is in on this conspiracy, right?
Well, why not?
Yeah, Earl Warren.
Hey, honey, I don't know Earl Warren.
Lyndon Johnson?
Lyndon Johnson is a politician.
You know the ethics those guys have.
It's like a notch underneath child molester.
Then everybody's in on the conspiracy.
The FBI and the CIA and J. Edgar Hoover...
and oil companies and the Pentagon
and the men's room attendant at the White House?
I would leave out the men's room attendant.
You're using this conspiracy theory
as an excuse to avoid sex with me.
Oh, my God.
She's right.
Why did I turn off Alison Porchnik?
She was beautiful, she was willing,
she was real, intelligent.
Is it the old Groucho Marx joke
that I just don't want to belong to any club
that would have someone like me for a member?
Albie, now don't panic, please.
I told you it's a mistake to ever bring a live thing in the house.
Stop it. Don't do that. Go to that one.
Maybe we should just call the police.
Dial 911. It's the lobster squad.
Come on, Albie. They're only baby ones, for God's sake.
If they're only babies, then you pick them up.
Oh, all right. All right. Here. Here you go.
Don't give it to me. Don't.
Look. One crawl behind the refrigerator.
It'll turn up in our bed at night.
Get out of here with that thing.
Jesus.
Talk to him. You speak shellfish.
Hey, look.
Put it in the pot.
I can't put it in the pot. I can't put a live thing in hot water.
Let me do it. What do you think we're gonna do?
Take it to the movies?
Oh, good, Abby. I'll save you.
Okay, it's in. It's definitely in the pot.
Annie, there's a big lobster behind the refrigerator.
I can't get it out. This thing's heavy.
Maybe if I put a little dish of butter sauce here with a nutcracker, it'll run out the other side.
I'm gonna get my camera. Hold on.
You know, I think if I could pry the floor up...
We should have gotten stakes, because they don't have legs.
They don't run around.
Ah! God! Jesus! Ow!
All right, all right.
Pick this lobster up. Hold it, please.
It'll make great...
You're gonna take pictures now?
It'll be wonderful. Oh, lovely!
Oh, God. That's disgusting.
One more, Ellie, please. One more thing.
Oh, oh, good! Good!
So, here's what I want to know.
Am I your first big romance?
Oh, no, no, no, uh-uh, no.
Really? Who was?
Oh, well, let's see.
There was Dennis from Chippewa Falls High School.
Dennis, right? Local kid, probably.
We meet you in front of the movie house on Saturday night.
Oh, God, you should have seen what I looked like then.
Oh, I can imagine. Probably the wife of an astronaut.
Then there was Jerry, the actor.
Look at you. You're such a clown.
I look pretty.
Well, yeah, you always look pretty,
but that guy with you...
Acting is like an exploration of the soul.
It's very religious.
Like a kind of liberating consciousness.
It's like a visual poem.
Is he kidding with that crap?
Oh, right.
Right, yeah, I think I know exactly what you mean when you say religious.
You do?
Oh, come on, I mean, I was younger.
Hey, that was last year.
It's like when I think of dying. You know how I'd like to die?
No, how?
I'd like to get torn apart by wild animals.
Oh, heavy, eaten by some squirrels.
Hey, listen, I mean, he was a terrific actor, and look at him.
He's neat-looking and he was emotional.
I don't think you like emotion too much.
Touch my heart with your foot.
I may throw up.
He was creepy.
Yeah. I think you're pretty lucky I came along.
Oh, really? Well, la-di-da.
La-di-da. If anyone had ever told me that I would be taking out a girl
who used expressions like la-di-da...
Oh, that's right. You really like those New York girls.
Well, no, not just. Not only.
Oh, I'd say so. You married two of them.
There's Henry Drucker.
He has a chair in history at Princeton.
Oh, and the short man is Herschel Kaminsky.
He has a chair in philosophy at Cornell.
Yeah, two more chairs. They got a dining room set.
Why are you so hostile?
Because I want to watch the Knicks on television.
Is that Paul Goodman?
No.
Be nice to the host because he's publishing my book.
Hi, Doug.
Douglas Wyeth.
The foul rag and bone shop of the heart.
I'm so tired of spending evenings making fake insights with people who work for dysentery.
Commentary.
Really? I heard that commentary and dissent had merged and formed dysentery.
No jokes. These are friends, okay?
Cleveland Cavaliers losing to the out-of-it New York Knicks.
Here you are.
There's people out there.
Two minutes ago, the Knicks are ahead 14 points, and now they're ahead two points.
Albie
what is so fascinating
about a group of pituitary cases
trying to stuff a ball through a hoop
what is fascinating
is that it's physical
you know it's one thing about intellectuals
they prove that you can be absolutely brilliant
and have no idea what's going on
but on the other hand
the body doesn't lie
as we now know
stop acting
it'll be great because all those PhDs
are in there you know like discussing
modes of alienation and we'll be in here quietly humping alvey don't you're using sex to express
hostility why do you always reduce my animal urges the psychoanalytic categories he said as he
removed her brassiere alvey there are people out there from the new yorker magazine oh my god
what do they think
Sorry.
Okay, don't get upset.
Damn it, I was so close.
Jesus, last night it was a guy honking his car horn.
I mean, the city can't close down.
What do you want me to do, have him shut down the airport too?
No more flights so we can have sex?
I'm too tense.
I need a Valium.
My analyst says I should live in the country and not in New York.
in New York. Well, I can't. We can't have this discussion all the time. The country makes me
nervous. There's, you got crickets and it's, it's quiet. There's no place to walk after dinner and
there's the screens with the dead moths behind them and you, you got the Manson family possibly
and you got Dick and Perry. Okay, okay. My analyst just thinks I'm too tense. Where's the goddamn
belly? Okay, come on. It's quiet now. I can't. My head is throbbing. Oh, you got a headache. I have
headache. Bad? Like Oswald in Ghosts. Where are you going? I'm gonna take another in a series of
cold showers. Max, my server's gonna send you to the showers early. Right, right. So to get back to
what we're discussing, the failure of the country to get behind New York City is anti-Semitism. Max,
the city is terribly run. But I'm not discussing politics or economics. This is foreskin. No, no,
Max, that's a very convenient out. Every time some group disagrees with you, it's because of
anti-semitism don't you see the rest of the country looks upon new york like we're we're
left-wing communist jewish homosexual pornographers i think of us that way sometimes and i live here
max if we lived in california we could play outdoors every day in the summer sun is bad
for you everything our parents said was good is bad sun milk red meat college
I know, but I... Oh, again, here it comes.
Okay. Oh, hi.
Hi. You're Albie?
Oh, hi, Albie. It's Janet.
This is Annie Hall. Hi.
Albie.
Who's playing with who here?
You and me against them?
Oh, I think that's not fair.
I've had four lessons.
Oh, yeah.
Hi.
Oh, hi.
Well, bye.
You play very well.
Oh, yeah?
So do you.
Oh, God, what a dumb thing to say, right?
I mean, you say you play well, and then right away,
I have to say, you play well.
Oh, oh, God, Annie.
Well, oh, well.
La-dee-da, la-dee-da, la-la, yeah.
You want a lift?
Oh, why?
You got a car?
No, I was going to take a cab.
Oh, no, I have a car.
You have a car?
So, Ernst, if you have a car,
So then why did you say, do you have a car,
like you wanted a Lyft?
I don't.
Geez, I don't know.
I wasn't.
Pfft.
I got this VW out there.
I don't.
What a jerk.
Yeah.
Would you like a Lyft?
Sure.
Which way are you going?
Me?
Downtown.
I'm going uptown.
Oh, well, you know I'm going uptown too.
You just said you were going downtown.
Yeah, well, but I can...
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I can go uptown, too.
I live uptown, but what the hell?
I mean, it'd be nice having company, you know?
I mean, I hate driving alone.
Yeah?
So how long do you know Janet?
Where do you know her from?
Oh, I'm an interactive class.
Oh, you're an actress.
Well, I do commercial service, you know?
One, two, three, four.
Yeah.
Well, you're not from New York, right?
No, Chippewa Falls.
Right.
Where?
Wisconsin.
Oh, you're driving a tad rapidly.
Yeah, don't worry.
I'm a very good driver.
I could.
So, listen, hey, you want some gum anywhere?
No, no thanks.
Hey, don't do that.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Would you watch the road?
I'll get it.
I'll get your piece.
So, listen, you drive?
Do I drive?
No, I got a problem with driving.
Oh, you do?
Yeah.
I got a license, but I have too much hostility.
Oh, right.
That's a good point.
Nice car.
You keep it nice.
Can I ask you, is this a sandwich?
Huh?
Oh, yeah.
I live over here.
Oh, my God, look, there's a parking space.
That's okay.
We can walk to the curb from here.
It'll be fine.
You want your tennis stuff?
Huh?
You want your gear?
Yeah, that's good.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Well...
Thank you.
You're a wonderful tennis player.
Oh.
You're the worst driver I've ever seen in my life.
That's any place, the worst.
Europe, you know, any place.
Asia.
Yeah.
And I love what you're wearing.
Oh, you do?
Yeah.
Oh, well, this tie is a present from Grammy Hall.
Who?
Grammy?
Grammy Hall?
Yeah, my Grammy.
What did you do?
Grow up in a Norman Rockwell painting?
Yeah, I know.
Your Grammy?
I know.
It's pretty silly.
She said, my Grammy never gave gifts, you know?
She was too busy getting raped by Cossacks.
Well, thank you again.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, well, listen, hey, you want to come upstairs
and have a glass of wine or something?
No, I mean, you don't have to.
You're probably late and everything.
No, no, I'll be fine. I don't mind.
Sure, I've got time.
I've got nothing to my analyst appointment.
Oh, wait, you see an analyst?
Yeah, just for 15 years.
15 years?
Yeah, I'm going to give him one more year,
and then I'm going to Lourdes.
15? Nah, come on.
Yeah? Really?
Sylvia Plath, interesting poetess whose tragic suicide
was misinterpreted as romantic by the college girl mentality.
Oh, yeah.
Sorry.
Right. Well, I don't know.
I mean, some of her poems seem neat.
Neat?
Neat, yeah.
I hate to tell you, this is 1975, you know.
Neat went out, I would say, at the turn of the century.
Who are those photos on the wall?
Oh, oh, well, you see, now, that's my dad, that's father,
and that's my brother, Dwayne.
Dwayne?
Yeah, right, Duane.
And over there is Grammy Hall.
And that's Sadie.
Who's Sadie?
Sadie?
Oh, well, Sadie.
Sadie met Grammy through Grammy's brother, George.
George was real sweet, you know.
He had that thing.
What is that thing where you fall asleep
in the middle of a sentence, you know?
What is it?
Narcolepsy.
Narcolepsy, right, right, right.
So anyway, so George went to the union, you see,
to get his free turkey.
Because the union always gave George this free turkey
at Christmas time because he was shell-shocked,
you know what I mean, in the First World War?
Anyway, so George is standing in line
getting his free turkey,
but the thing is that he falls asleep
and he never wakes up,
so he's dead.
He's dead.
Yeah.
Oh, dear.
Well, terrible, huh, wouldn't you say?
I mean, that's pretty awful.
It's a great story, though.
I mean, I really made my day.
Hey, I think I should get out of here, you know,
because I think I'm imposing, you know?
Oh, really? Oh, well, maybe, uh...
You know, I...
Well, I mean, you don't have to, you know.
No, I know, but, you know, I'm all perspired and everything.
Well, didn't you take a shower at the club?
I mean, no, no, no, because I never shower in a public place.
Why not?
Because I don't like to get naked in front of another man, you know?
It's, uh...
Oh, I see, I see.
You know, I don't like to show my body to a man of my gender.
Yeah, I see, I guess.
You never know what's gonna happen.
15 years, huh?
15 years, yeah.
Oh.
God bless.
Well, you're what Grammy Hall would call a real Jew.
Thank you.
Yeah, well, you know, she hates Jews.
She thinks that they just make money.
But let me tell you, I mean, she's the one.
Is she ever, I'm telling you.
So, did you do those photographs in there, or what?
Yeah, yeah, I sort of dabble around, you know.
They're wonderful, you know, they have a quality.
Well, I would like to take a serious photography course.
Photography's interesting, because, you know, it's a new art form,
and a set of aesthetic criteria have not emerged yet.
Aesthetic criteria? You mean whether it's a good photo or not?
The medium enters in as a condition of the art form itself.
Well, to me, I mean, it's all instinctive.
I just try to feel it. I try to get a sense of it and not think about it so much.
Still, you need a set of aesthetic guidelines to put it in social perspective, I think.
Well, I don't know. I guess you must be sort of late, huh?
You know what?
I've got to get there and begin whining soon, otherwise.
Are you busy Friday night?
Me? Oh. Uh, no.
Oh, I'm sorry. Wait a minute. I have something.
What about Saturday night?
Oh.
Nothing. Not... No. No.
You're very popular, I can see.
I know.
Boy, you have plague.
Well, I mean, I meet a lot of jerks.
Do you? I meet a lot of jerks, too.
I think that's a...
But I'm thinking about getting some cats, you know, and then...
Oh, wait a second. Oh, no, no. I mean, oh, shoot.
No, Saturday night I'm gonna...
I'm gonna sing.
You're gonna sing? Do you sing?
No kidding.
This is my first time.
Oh, really? Where? Well, I'd like to come.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, I'm interested.
Oh, no, I mean, I'm just...
I'm auditioning sort of at this club. I don't...
No, it's my first time.
That's okay, because I know exactly what that's like.
Listen, you're gonna like nightclubs. They're really a lot of fun.
It had to be you.
I wandered around and finally found
There's somebody who
Could make me be true
Could make me be blue
And even be glad
Just to be sad
Thinking of you
I was awful. I'm so ashamed. I can't think.
Oh, listen, so the audience was a tad restless.
What do you mean a tad restless? Oh, my God. I mean, they hated me.
No, they didn't. You have a wonderful voice.
No, I'm going to quit.
I'm not going to let you. You have a great voice.
Really? Do you think so? Really?
Yeah.
Yeah?
It's terrific.
Yeah, you know something? I never even took a lesson either.
Hey, listen. Listen. Give me a kiss.
Really?
Yeah, why not? Because we're just gonna go home later, right?
And there's gonna be all that tension, you know, we never kissed before,
and I'll never know when to make the right move or anything.
So we'll kiss now, we'll get it over with, then we'll go eat, okay?
We'll digest our food better.
Okay.
Okay? So now we can digest our food.
Digest it?
Yeah.
I'm gonna have a corned beef, please.
Oh, I'm gonna have pastrami on white bread with mayonnaise and tomatoes and lettuce.
So, um, your second wife left you, and were you depressed about that?
Nothing that a few megavitamins couldn't cure.
And your first wife, was it Allison?
Yeah, she was nice, but, you know, that was my fault. I was too crazy.
That was so nice. That was nice.
As Balzac said, there goes another novel.
You were great.
Oh, yeah? Yeah?
Yeah, I'm wrecked.
You're wrecked.
I mean it. I will never play the piano again.
It was... I don't know. You really thought it was good?
Good, yes. No.
No, that was the most fun I've ever had without laughing.
Here, you want some?
No, no, I don't use any major hallucinogenics.
I took a puff about five years ago at a party.
Yeah?
I tried to take my pants off over my head.
Not one ear.
Well, I don't know.
I don't really...
I don't do it very often.
It just sort of relaxes me.
You're not going to believe this, but...
What?
Hey.
I'm going to buy you these books, I think,
because I think you should read them.
You know, instead of that cat book.
That's pretty serious stuff there.
Yeah, because I'm obsessed with death, I think.
It's a big subject with me, yeah.
I have a very pessimistic view of life.
You should know this about me if we're going to go out.
You know, I feel that life is divided up into the horrible and the miserable.
Those are the two categories, you know.
The horrible would be like, I don't know, terminal cases, you know,
and blind people and cripples.
I don't know how they get through life.
It's amazing to me.
You know, and the miserable is everyone else.
So when you go through life, you should be thankful that you're miserable.
Because you're very lucky to be miserable.
Look at that guy.
There's Mr. in the pink.
Mr. Miami Beach there.
He's just come back from the gin rummy finals.
He's placed third.
Look at these guys.
Oh, that's hilarious.
They're back from Fire Island.
They're sort of giving it a chance.
Oh, Italian, right?
Him?
Yeah, he's the mafia.
Linen supply business or cement and contracting, I think.
Oh, gee.
I just had my mustache waxed.
Well, there's the winner of the Truman Capote look-alike contest.
You are extremely sexy.
Unbelievably sexy.
Yes, you are.
Because you know what you are?
You're polymorphously perverse.
What does that mean?
I don't know what that is.
You're exceptional in bed because you get pleasure in every part of your body when I touch it.
You know what I mean?
Like the tip of your nose and if I stroke your teeth or your kneecaps, you suddenly get excited.
You know what? You know, I like you. I really do like you.
Do you love me? That's a key question.
I know you've only known me a short while.
I think that's sort of... Yeah. Yeah.
Do you love me?
Love is too weak a word for...
I love you. I loave you. I love you.
Two Fs. I have to invent... Of course I... Don't you think I do?
I don't know.
What do you mean? You're not going to give up your own apartment, are you?
Of course.
Yeah, but why?
Well, I'm moving in with you. That's why.
Yeah, but you've got a nice apartment.
I have a tiny apartment.
I know it's small.
That's right. It's got bad plumbing and bugs.
All right, granted, it has bad plumbing and bugs,
but you say that like it's a negative thing.
You know, bugs are...
Entomology is a rapidly growing field.
You don't want me to live with you.
How? I don't want you to live with me.
Whose idea was it?
Come on.
Yeah.
It was yours, actually, but I approved it immediately.
I guess you think that I talked you into something, huh?
No.
What do you...
We live together.
We sleep together.
We eat together.
Jesus, you don't want it to be like we're married, do you?
How is it any different?
It's different because you keep your own apartment.
Because, you know, it's there.
We don't have to go to it.
We don't have to deal with it.
But it's like a free-floating life raft that we know that we're not married.
That little apartment is $400 a month, Albie.
That place is $400 a month?
Yes, it is.
It's got bad plumbing and bugs.
Jesus.
My accountant will write off as a tax deduction.
I'll pay for it.
You don't think I'm smart enough to be serious about?
Hey, don't be ridiculous.
Then why are you always pushing me to take those college courses
like I was dumb or something?
Because adult education's a wonderful thing.
You meet a lot of interesting professors.
You know, it's stimulating.
Does this sound like a good course on modern American poetry?
Or, let's see now, maybe I should take introduction to the novel.
Just don't take any course where they make you read Beowulf.
What?
Hey, listen, what do you think?
You think we should go to that party in Southampton?
Oh, don't be silly.
What do we need other people for?
You know, we should just turn out the lights, you know,
and play hide the salam or something.
Well, okay, well, it's time to get a cigarette, okay?
Oh, grass, right?
The illusion that it will make a white woman more like Billie Holiday.
Well, have you ever made love high?
Me? No.
You know, if I have grass or alcohol or anything,
I get unbearably wonderful.
I get too, too wonderful for words.
I don't know why you have to get high every time we make love.
It relaxes me.
You have to be artificially relaxed before we can go to bed?
Well, what's the difference anyway?
Well, I'll give you a shot of sodium pentothal.
You can sleep through it.
Oh, come on. Look who's talking.
You've been seeing a psychiatrist for 15 years.
You should smoke some of this.
You'd be off the couch in no time.
Oh, come on. You don't need that.
What are you doing?
Oh, no, no, no.
You can live with that at once.
Oh.
Wait. I got a great idea.
Hang in there for a second.
and I got a little artifact, a little erotic artifact
that I brought up from the city,
which I think is gonna be perfect.
I just, there, create a little old New Orleans essence.
Now we can go about our business here
and even develop photographs if we want to.
Just stay.
Oh, thanks.
Hey, is something wrong?
No, why?
I don't know. It's like you removed.
No, I'm fine.
Really?
Uh-huh.
No, no, no. You seem sort of distant.
Let's just do it, all right?
Was it my imagination, or are you just going through the motions?
Alvy, do you remember where I put my drawing pad?
Because while you two are doing that, I think I'm going to do some drawing.
You see, that's what I call removed.
Oh, you have my body.
Yeah, but that's how I want the whole thing.
Well, I need grass.
Well, it ruins it for me if you have grass,
because, you know, I'm like a comedian,
so if I get a laugh from a person who's high,
it doesn't count, you know, because they're always laughing.
Were you always funny?
Hey, what is this, an interview?
We're supposed to be making love.
This guy is naturally funny.
I think he can write for you.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, Kitty, tell me you're really good.
Well, let me explain a little bit of how I work.
You know, you can tell right off the bat
that I don't look like a funny guy when I go, you know,
like some of the guys that come out.
You know right away they're gonna tell you their stories, you're gonna fall down.
But I gotta be really talented.
Material's gotta be sensational for me because I work, you know, with very, very, I'm kind of classy.
You know what I mean?
Let me explain.
For instance, I'll open an opening song.
The music will start like, and I walk up, the place looks wonderful from here.
And you folks look wonderful from here.
And seeing you there with a smile on your face makes me shout, this must be the place.
And I stop right in the middle and then I open with some jokes.
Now that's where I need you right there.
Princess, like I say. Hey, I just got back from Canada.
You know, they speak a lot of French up there.
The only way to remember is Jean d'Arc.
Means the light's out in the bathroom.
Oh, I met a big lumberjack.
Jesus, this guy's pathetic.
Look at him mincing around.
Boy, he thinks he's real cute.
You want to throw up.
If only I had the nerve to do my own jokes.
I don't know how much longer I can keep this smile frozen on my face.
I'm in the wrong business. I know it.
but, uh,
chérie,
what will I do with this, eh?
He says, oh, Marie,
sometime you'll make me so mad.
Oh, they scream at that.
Now, write me something like that.
Will you kind of a French number?
Can you do it?
Okay.
Where am I?
I keep, I have to reorient myself
because this is the University of Wisconsin, right?
Because I'm always, I'm tense
and when I'm playing a college.
I have a very bad history with colleges.
You know, I went to New York University
and I was thrown out of NYU my freshman year
for cheating on my metaphysics final.
You know, I looked within the soul
of the boy sitting next to me.
Found that out there.
And when I was thrown out,
my mother, who's an emotionally high-strung woman,
locked herself in the bathroom
and took an overdose of Mahjong tiles.
You know, jammed them down.
And I was depressed at that time.
I was in analysis.
I was suicidal, as a matter of fact,
and would have killed myself,
but I was in analysis with a strict Freudian,
and if you kill yourself,
they make you pay for the sessions you miss.
Alvy, you were just great.
I'm not kidding.
It was...
You were so great.
College audiences are wonderful.
Yeah, yeah.
And you know something?
I think that I'm starting to get more of the references, too.
Are you?
Yeah.
Well, the 12 o'clock show is completely different than mine.
Oh, I'm really looking forward to tomorrow.
I mean, you know, I think it'll be really nice.
You'll meet mother and father.
Yeah, I know. They'll hate me immediately.
Yeah, no, I don't think so.
No, I don't think they're going to hate you at all.
Contrary, I think it's Easter, you know, we'll have a nice dinner.
We'll sit down and eat.
I think they're going to really like you.
It's a nice ham this year, Mom.
Oh, yeah.
Grammy always does such a good job.
Great sauce.
It is. It's dynamite, Ann.
We went over to the swap room.
Annie, Graham and I got some nice picture frames.
We really had a good time.
Ann tells us that you've been seeing a psychiatrist for 15 years.
Yes, I'm making excellent progress.
Pretty soon when I lie down on his couch, I won't have to wear the lobster bib.
Duane and I went out to the boat basin.
We were caulking holes all day.
And Randolph Hunt was drunk, as usual.
Oh, that Randolph Hunt.
You remember Randy Hunt, Annie?
He was in the choir with you.
Oh, yes.
I can't believe this family.
Annie's mother is really beautiful.
And they're talking swap meets and boat basins.
and the old lady at the end of the table is a classic Jew hater.
And they really look American, you know, very healthy.
They never get sick or anything.
Nothing like my family.
The two are like oil and water.
Ah, let him drive, Dan. Who needs his business?
His wife has diabetes.
Diabetes?
Jack Adams is the new president.
Is that an excuse, diabetes?
Let me tell you, a man is 50 years old and doesn't have a substantial job.
Oh, yes, that's right.
What are you talking about?
You know what you're talking about.
Sure, defend him.
You remember her.
We're in 4-H.
He had a coronary.
How do you plan to spend the holidays, Mrs. Singer?
We fast.
Fast?
No food.
To atone for our sins.
What sins? I don't understand.
Tell you the truth. Neither do we.
I'll be.
Hi, Dwayne. How's it going?
This is my room.
Oh, yeah, it's terrific.
Can I confess something?
I tell you this because as an artist, I think you'll understand.
Sometimes when I'm driving, on the road at night,
I see two headlights coming toward me.
Fast, I have this sudden impulse to turn the wheel quickly,
head on into the oncoming car.
I can anticipate the explosion, the sound of shattering glass,
the flames rising out of the flowing gasoline.
Right.
Well, I have to go now, Duane, because I'm due back on the planet Earth.
Oh, let it be so long now.
No, and look up Uncle Brilly.
Oh, he is adorable.
Do you think so, really?
We're going to take them to the airport.
No, no, Duane can. I haven't finished my drink.
Yes, Duane is. I'll be right...
Just a second. I have to get the air.
You followed me. I can't believe it.
I didn't follow you.
You followed me.
Why? Because I was walking along a block behind you, staring at you?
That's not following.
Well, what is your definition of following?
Following is different. I was spying.
Do you realize how paranoid you are?
Paranoid? I'm looking at you. You've got your arms around another guy.
That is the worst kind of paranoia.
Jesus. Well, I didn't start out spying.
I thought I'd surprise you, pick you up after school.
Yeah, well, you wanted to keep the relationship flexible.
Remember, it's your phrase.
Oh, stop it. You're having an affair with your college professor,
that jerk that teaches that incredible crap course,
Contemporary Crisis in Western Manor.
Existential motifs in Russian literature. You're really close.
What's the difference? It's all mental masturbation.
Oh, well, now we're finally getting to a subject you know something about.
Hey, don't knock masturbation. It's sex with someone I love.
We're not having an affair. He's married. He just happens to think I'm neat.
Neat. What are you, 12 years old? That's one of your Chippewa Falls expressions.
Who cares? Who cares?
Next thing you know, we'll find you're keen and peachy, you know?
Next thing you know, he's got his hand on your ass.
You've always had hostility towards David, ever since I mentioned him.
You call your teacher David?
It's his name.
Well, listen, I said, it's a biblical name, right?
What does he call you, Bathsheba?
Alvy. Alvy, you're the one who never wanted to make a real commitment.
You don't think I'm smart enough.
We had that argument just last month, but don't you remember that day?
I'm home.
Oh, yeah? How'd it go?
Oh, it was really weird, but she's a very nice woman.
And I didn't have to lie down on the couch, Alvy.
She had me sitting up.
So I told her about the family and about my feelings towards men
and about my relationship with my brother.
And then she mentioned penis envy.
Do you know about that?
Me? I'm one of the few males who suffers from that.
So, you know, go on.
Well, she said that I was very guilty
about my impulses towards marriage and children.
And then I remembered when I was a kid
how I accidentally saw my parents making love.
Really? All this happened the first hour?
That's amazing.
I've been gone for 15 years.
You know, I don't have nothing like that.
I told her my dream, and then I cried.
You cried? I have never once cried.
That's fantastic to me. I whine. I sit in my room.
Well, anyway, Albie, in my dream,
Frank Sinatra is holding this pillow across my face, and I can't breathe.
Sinatra?
Yeah, and it's strangling me, and I can't, you know, it's just...
No kidding. Well, sure, because he's a singer and you're a singer, you know?
So it's perfect. So you're trying to suffocate yourself.
It makes perfect sense. It's a perfect analytic kind of insight.
She said your name was Albie Singer.
What do you mean? Me?
Well, yeah, yeah, you, because in the dream, I break Sinatra's glasses.
Sinatra had glasses?
You never said Sinatra had glasses.
What are you saying, that I'm suffocating you?
Oh, and God, Albie, I did this really terrible thing to him
because then when he sang,
it was in this real high-pitched voice.
So what did the doctor say?
Well, she said that I should probably come five times a week.
And you know something?
I don't think I mind analysis at all.
The only question is, is will it change my wife?
Will it change your wife?
Will it change my life?
Yeah, but you said, will it change my wife?
No, I didn't. I said, will it change my life, Albie?
You said, will it change... Wife.
Life. I said life.
She said, will it change my wife.
You heard that because you were there, so I'm not crazy.
And then I told her about how I didn't think you'd ever really take me seriously
because you don't think that I'm smart enough.
Why do you always bring that up?
Because I encourage you to take adult education courses?
I think it's a wonderful thing.
You meet wonderful, interesting professors.
Adult education is such junk.
The professors are so phony. How can you do it?
I don't care what you say about David.
He's a perfectly fine teacher.
What are you doing following me around for anyway?
I was following you and David.
I think we better call this relationship quick.
That's fine. That's fine. That's great.
Well, I don't know what I did wrong.
I mean, I can't believe this.
Somewhere she cooled off to me.
Is it something that I did?
Never something you do.
That's how people are.
Love fades.
God, that's a depressing thought.
I have to ask you a question.
Don't go any further.
With your wife in bed,
does she need some kind of artificial stimulation like marijuana?
We use a large vibrating egg.
Large vibrating egg. Well, I ask a psychopath, I get that kind of an answer.
Jesus, I... Here, you look like a very happy couple.
Um, are you? Yeah.
Yeah? So how do you account for it?
Uh, I'm very shallow and empty, and I have no ideas and nothing interesting to say.
Well, I'm exactly the same way.
I see. Well, that's very interesting. So you've managed to work out something, huh?
Right. Oh.
Thanks very much for talking to me.
You know, even as a kid, I always went for the wrong women.
I think that's my problem.
When my mother took me to see Snow White,
everyone fell in love with Snow White.
I immediately fell for the wicked queen.
We never have any fun anymore.
How can you say that?
Why not? You're always leaning on me to improve myself.
You're just upset. You must be getting your period.
I don't get a period. I'm a cartoon character.
Can't I be upset once in a while?
Max, will you forget about Annie?
I know lots of women you can date.
I don't want to go out with any other women.
Max, I have got a girl for you.
You are going to love her.
She's a reporter for Rolling Stone.
I think there are more people here to see the Maharishi
than there were to see the Dylan concert.
I covered the Dylan concert, which gave me chills.
Especially when he sang,
she takes just like a woman,
and she makes love just like a woman.
Yes, she does.
and she aches just like a woman,
but she breaks just like a little girl.
Up to that, I guess the most charismatic event I covered
was Mick's birthday
when the Stones played Madison Square Garden.
That's great. That's just great.
You catch Dylan?
Me? No, no, I couldn't make it.
My raccoon had hepatitis.
You have a raccoon?
A few.
The only word for this is transplendent.
It's transplendent.
I can think of another word.
He's God. I mean, this man is God.
He's got millions of followers who would crawl all the way across the world just to touch the hem of his garment.
Yeah, it must be a tremendous hem.
I'm a Rosicrucian myself.
Are you?
Yeah.
I can't get with any religion that advertises in popular mechanics.
Look, there's God coming out of the men's room.
It's unbelievably transplendent.
I was at the Stones concert in Altamont when they killed that guy, remember?
Yeah, were you?
I was at an Alice Cooper thing where six people were rushed to the hospital with bad vibes.
I hope you don't mind that I took so long to finish.
No, don't be silly.
You know, I'm starting to get some feeling back in my jaw now.
Sex with you is really a Kafkaesque experience.
Oh, thank you.
I mean that as a compliment.
I think there's too much burden placed on the orgasm, you know,
to make up for empty areas in life.
Who said that?
I don't know. It may have been Leopold and Loeb.
Hello?
Oh, hi.
Uh, no. What...
What's the matter?
What... What's... You sound terrible.
No, what... Shrek...
What kind of emergency?
No, well, stay there. Stay there. I'll come over right...
No, I'll come over right now. Just stay there. I'll come right over.
What's... What's me? Oh, my God.
Oh, I'm sorry. Are you okay? What's the matter?
Are you all right? What... There's a spider in the bathroom.
What? There's a big spider.
black spider in the bathroom.
That's what you got me here for at 3 o'clock in the morning
because there's a spider in the bathroom?
Oh, my God. I mean, you know how I am about insects.
I can't sleep with a live thing crawling around in the bathroom.
Just kill it. For God's... What's wrong with you?
Don't you have a can of Raid in the house?
No.
I told you a thousand times
you should always keep a lot of insect spray.
You never know who's gonna crawl over.
I know, I know.
And a first-aid kit and a fire extinguisher.
All right, give me a magazine because I'm a little tired.
You know, you joke with him about me, you make fun of me,
but I'm prepared for anything, an emergency, a tidal wave, an earthquake.
Hey, what is this?
Did you go to a rock concert?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah, really?
Really? How'd you like it?
Was it, I mean, was it heavy?
Did it achieve total heaviosity, or was it...
It was just great.
Oh, I've got a wonderful idea.
Why don't you get the guy that took you to the rock concert,
we'll call him, and he can come over and kill the spider.
You know, it's a...
I called you. You want to help me or not, huh?
What is this? Since when do you read the National Review?
What are you turning into?
Well, I like to try to get all points of view.
Wonderful. Then why don't you get William F. Buckley to kill the spider?
Alvy, you're a little hostile. You know that?
Not only that, you look thin and tired.
Well, I was in... It's 3 o'clock in the morning.
You got me out of bed. I ran over here.
I couldn't get a taxi cab. You said it was an emergency.
I ran up the stairs.
I was a lot more attractive when the evening began.
What are you, are you going with a right wing rock and roll star?
Would you like a glass of chocolate milk?
Hey, what am I, your son?
What do you mean?
I came over for a...
I got the good chocolate.
Yeah, where's the spider?
It's in the bathroom.
Is it in the bathroom?
Okay.
Hey, don't squish it, and after it's dead,
flush it down the toilet, okay?
And flush it a couple of times.
Darling, I've been killing spiders since I was 30, okay?
It's a very big spider.
Yeah?
Yeah, a lot of trouble.
There's two of them.
Yep, I didn't think it was that big, but it's a major spider.
You got a broom or something with a snow shovel?
Oh, it's at your house. I think I left it there. I'm sorry.
What are you doing? What are you doing?
Honey, there's a spider in your bathroom the size of a Buick.
Oh, okay.
Hey.
What is this? You got black soap?
It's for my complexion.
What are you joining a minstrel show?
Don't worry.
I did it. I killed them both.
What's the matter? What are you sad about?
What do you want me to do, capture them and rehabilitate them?
Oh, don't go, okay? Please.
What do you mean, don't go? What's the matter?
What are you, expecting termites?
What's the matter?
I don't know. I miss you.
Oh, Jesus. Really?
Oh, yeah.
Alvy?
What?
Was there somebody in your room when I called you?
What do you mean?
I mean, was there another... I thought I heard a voice.
No, I had the radio on.
Yeah?
I'm sorry, the television. I was watching the show.
Yeah.
Alvy, let's never break up again.
I don't want to be apart.
I know. I think we're both much too mature for something like that.
Living together hasn't been so bad, has it?
No, for me it's been terrific, you know?
Better than either one of my marriages, you know?
This is just something different about you. I don't know why it's great
You know, I think that if you let me maybe I could help you have more fun
You know, I mean, I know it's hard
Albie what about what if we go away this weekend?
Why don't we get why don't we get Rob and the three of us would drive into Brooklyn?
You know, we show you the old neighborhood. Okay fun for you
You got total a whole car.
Hey, you know, I never even been to Brooklyn before.
I can't wait to see the old neighborhood.
Yeah, the neighborhood's gonna be great.
We could show her the schoolyard.
Right, I was a great athlete.
Tell her, Max, I was the best.
I was all schoolyard.
Yes, I remember.
He was all schoolyard.
They threw him a football once.
He tried to dribble it.
Yeah, well, I used to lose my glasses a lot.
Oh, look, look.
That's my old house.
That's where I used to live.
Holy cow.
You're lucky, Max.
Where I used to live is now a pornographic equipment store.
Max, I had some very good memories there.
What kind of good memories, Max?
Your mother and father fighting all the time.
Yeah, and always over the most ridiculous things.
You fired the cleaning woman?
She was stealing!
But she's colored!
So?
So the colored have enough trouble!
She was going through my pocketbook!
They're persecuted enough!
Who's persecuting?
She stole!
All right, so?
We can afford it?
How can we afford it?
On your pay?
What if she steals more?
She's a colored woman from Harlem!
She has no money!
She's got a right to steal from us!
After all, who is he going to steal from if not us?
You're both crazy.
I can't hear you, Max.
Leo, I married a fool.
Hey, Max, what's that?
That's the welcome home party, 1945, for my cousin Herbie.
Look, there's that over there.
That's Joey Nichols.
He was my father's friend.
He was always bothering me when I was a kid.
Joey Nichols.
See? Nichols.
You see, Nichols, you can always remember my name
Just think of Joey Five Cents
That's me, Joey Five Cents
What an asshole
The one who killed me the most was my mother's sister, Tessie
I was always the sister with good common sense
But Tessie was always the one with personality
When she was younger, they all wanted to marry Tessie
Can you believe that, Max? Tessie Moskowitz had the personality
She's the life of the ghetto, no doubt
She was once a great beauty.
Tessie, they say you were the sister with personality.
I was a great beauty.
How did this personality come about?
I was very charming.
There were many men interested in you?
Oh, I was quite a lively dancer.
That's very hard to believe.
Well, I had a really good day, you know that?
It was just a real fine way to spend my birthday.
Ah, well, your birthday's not till tomorrow, honey.
Yeah, but it's real close.
Yeah, but no presents till midnight.
Oh, come on, man.
Oh, this is...
Happy birthday.
What is this?
Is this a present?
Are you kidding?
Yeah.
Why don't you try it on?
This is more like a present for you.
Yeah, buddy.
It's more sex-like.
Uh-huh, yeah.
I forget it.
Here's a real present.
What?
Oh, yeah?
What is this, anyway?
Huh?
Check it out.
Let me see.
Oh, okay.
Let's see.
Oh, God! Oh, you knew I wanted this!
God, it's terrific! God!
Just put on the watch and the thing and it'll be fine.
Oh, God.
Seems like old times
Having you to walk with seems like old times.
Having you to walk with
And it's still a thrill
Just to have my arms around you
Still the thrill
That it was the day I found you
Seems like old times
Dinner dates and flowers
Old times
Staying up all hours
Making dreams come true
Doing things we used to do
Seems like old times
Here with you
Thank you.
You were sensational.
I mean, you know, I told you that if you stuck to it, you would be great.
And, you know, you were sensational.
Yeah, well, Albie, I mean, they were just a terrific audience.
I mean, you know, it makes it really easy for me because I can be...
Excuse me.
Oh.
Hi, I'm Tony Lacey.
Well, hi.
We just wanted to stop by and say that we really enjoyed your set.
Oh, yeah, really?
I thought it was very musical.
Oh, yes.
I liked it a lot.
Oh, that's really nice.
Gosh, thanks a lot.
Are you recording?
Are you with any label now?
Me?
No.
No, no, not at all.
Oh, well, I'd like to talk to you about that sometime
if you get a chance and possibly working together.
Well, hey, that's nice.
Oh, listen, this is Alvy Singer. Do you know Alvy?
No, I don't know, but I know you work. I'm a big fan of yours.
Thank you very much. A pleasure.
This is Sean and Bob and Petronia.
Hi, Bob.
We're going back to the pier. We're staying at the pier,
and we're gonna meet Jack and Angelica and have a drink there.
And if you'd like to come, we'd love to have you.
We can just sit and talk, nothing.
Not a big deal.
Let's just relax, just be very mellow.
Remember we had that thing?
What thing?
Don't you remember we discussed that thing that we were...
Thing?
Yes, we had it.
Oh, the thing.
Yeah.
if it's inconvenient and if you can't do it now,
that's fine, too.
We'll do it another time.
Maybe if you're on the coast, we'll get together
and we'll meet there.
It was a wonderful set.
Oh, gosh.
I really enjoyed it.
Nice to meet you.
Good night.
Bye-bye.
Bye.
Yeah, bye.
What's the matter?
What, you wanted to go to that party?
I don't know.
I thought it might be kind of fun.
You know, I mean, it would be nice to meet some new people.
I'm just not.
You know, I don't think I could take a mellow eat because I don't respond well to mellow.
You know, I mean, I have a tendency to, if I get too mellow, I ripen and then rot.
You know, and it's not good for my...
All right, all right, so you don't want to go to the party, so what do you want to do?
Kriegshetzer und Pariser Plutokraten wollten die Koffer voller Goldbarren und Edelsteine mit diesen Fahrzeugen entfliehen.
That day in Brooklyn was the last day I remember really having a good time.
We never have any laughs anymore is the problem.
I've been moody and dissatisfied.
How often do you sleep together?
Do you have sex often?
Hardly ever.
Maybe three times a week.
Constantly.
I'd say three times a week.
Like the other night, Albie wanted to have sex.
She would not sleep with me the other night, you know?
And I don't know.
I mean, six months ago, I would have done it.
I would have done it.
Just to please her.
I tried everything.
You know, I put on soft music and my red light bulb.
But the thing is, I mean, since our discussion's here,
I feel I have a right to my own feelings.
I think you would have been happy
because I really asserted myself.
The incredible thing about it is I'm paying for her analysis
and she's making progress and I'm getting screwed.
I don't know, though.
I mean, I feel so guilty because Alvy is paying for it,
so, you know, so I do feel guilty
if I don't go to bed with him.
But if I do go to bed with him,
it's like I'm going against my own feelings.
She's making progress and I'm not making any progress.
I can't win.
Then her progress is killing my progress.
Sometimes I think I should just live with a woman.
Wow, I don't believe it.
You mean to tell me you guys have never snorted coke?
Well, I always wanted to try, you know, but Albie, he's wearing down on it.
Don't put it on me.
I don't want to put a wad of white powder in my nose.
There's the nasal membrane.
You never want to try anything new, Al.
How can you say that?
I said that you and that girl from your acting class should sleep together.
Well, that's sick.
Yeah, I know it's sick, but it's new.
You didn't say it couldn't be sick.
Just come on, Albie.
Do your body a favor. Try it.
Yeah, come on.
I'm sure it's a lot of fun because the Incas did it, you know, and they were a million laughs.
Albie, come on, for your own experience. I mean, you won a ride.
It's great stuff, Albie. A friend of mine just brought it in from California.
Oh, you know something? I didn't tell you. We're going to California next week.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
I'm thrilled, as you know.
On my agent's advice, I sold out and I'm going to do an appearance on a TV show.
No, no.
No, that's not it at all. Albie's giving an award on television.
Geez, you act like you're violating a moral issue here.
It's so phony and we have to leave New York during Christmas week, which really kills me.
Alvy, listen.
While you're in California, could you possibly score some coke for me?
Oh, sure. I'd be glad to.
I'll just put it on a hollow heel that I have on my boot.
How much is this stuff?
That's about $2,000 an ounce.
Really? And what is the kick of it?
I never...
And so...
We wish you a Merry Christmas
I've never been so relaxed as I have been since I moved out here, Max.
I want you to see my house.
I live right next to Hugh Hefner's house, Max.
What's me is the jacuzzi.
And the women, Max, they're like the women in Playboy magazine,
only they can move their arms and legs.
You know, I can't get over that this is really Beverly Hills.
The architecture's really consistent, isn't it?
French next to Spanish next to Tudor next to Japanese.
God, it's so clean out here.
It's because they don't throw their garbage away.
They make it into television shows.
Oh, come on, Max.
Give us a break, will you?
It's Christmas.
Can you believe this is Christmas here?
You know, it was snowing.
It was snowing and really gray in New York, naturally.
No kidding.
Nice.
Santa Claus will have sunstroke.
Max, there's no crime.
There's no mugging.
There's no economic crime, you know,
but there's ritual religious cult murders.
You know, there's wheat germ killers out here.
While you're out here, Max,
I want you to see some of my TV show.
And we're invited to a big Christmas party.
We remember Christ our Savior
Was born on Christmas Day
To save us all from Satan's power
When we were gone astray
Now, Charlie, give me a good laugh here.
The limousine to the track breakdown?
A little bigger.
Max, you realize how immoral this all is?
Max, I got a hit series.
Yeah, but you're adding fake laughs.
You moved home so early.
Arnie.
Yeah, give me a tremendous laugh here, Tommy.
Let me see you trickle it down.
We're doing the show live in front of an audience.
Right, but nobody laughs at it, because the jokes aren't funny.
Yeah, well, that's why this machine is dynamite.
Arnie, you better lie down.
You've been in the sun too long.
Yeah.
Now, give me, like, a medium-sized chuckle here.
And then a big hand.
Is there booing on that?
You didn't know.
Oh, man.
We're just going to fix you up with my cousin Dolores.
I don't feel well. What's the matter?
I don't know. I just got... I got very dizzy.
You're not marrying Dolores.
I feel dizzy, Max.
What's the matter?
Oh, Jesus.
He's marrying Dolores.
Oh.
All right. I don't know.
You want to lie down?
No, no. You know, my stomach felt queasy all morning.
I just said I'd get out.
How about a ginger ale?
Oh, Max, no. Maybe I'd better lie down.
Yes.
Why don't you just try to get a little of this down?
Is it just plain chicken?
Oh, no. I can't eat this. I'm nauseous.
Oh, if you could just give me something to get me through the next two hours.
You know, I have to go out to Burbank and give out an award on a TV show.
There's nothing wrong with you, actually, so far as I can tell.
I mean, you have no fever, no symptoms of anything serious?
Yes, sir.
You haven't been eating pork or shellfish?
Excuse me, I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Doctor.
Alvy, Alvy, that was the show. They said everything is fine.
They found a replacement, so they're going to tape without you.
Oh, Jesus, now I don't get to do the TV show?
Oh, Christ.
Nothing at all?
No, I think I could get a lab man.
I'm a salt piece.
Excuse me.
Perhaps it would be even better if we took him to the hospital.
Oh, God.
Hospital?
Well, otherwise there's no real way to tell what's going on.
This is not bad, actually.
Hey, don't tell me we're going to have to walk from the car to the house.
Jeez, my feet haven't touched pavement since I reached Los Angeles.
Well, you take a meeting with him.
I'll take a meeting with you if you'll take a meeting with Freddy.
I took a meeting with Freddy.
Freddy took a meeting with Charlie.
You take a meeting with him.
All the good meetings are taken.
Right now, it's only an ocean.
But I think I can get money to make it into a concept
and then later turn it into an idea.
Like this house, Max?
Mm-hmm.
He even brought a road map to get us to the bathroom.
You should have told me it was Tony Lacey's party.
What do you mean?
I think he has a little thing for Annie.
No, no, no.
Unfortunately, Max, he goes with that girl over there.
Where?
The one with the VPL.
VPL?
Visible panty line.
Max, she's gorgeous.
Yeah, she's a 10, Max.
That's great for you, because you're used to twos, aren't you?
Yeah, they're all good twos, Max.
Yeah, you're used to the kind with the shopping bags,
walking through Central Park with the surgical masks on, muttering.
I like this couple, Max.
They just came back from Masters and Shops.
Yeah, intensive care wood.
My God.
Hey, Max, I think she's giving me the eye.
If she comes over here, Max, my brain's going to turn into guacamole.
I'll handle it, handle it.
Hi. Hi. You're Albie Singer, right?
Didn't we meet at Est? Est? No, no, no.
I was never to Est.
How could you criticize him?
Oh, he didn't say anything.
No, no, no. I came out to get some shock therapy,
but there was an energy crisis.
He's my food taster. Have you two met?
Hey, how do you do?
Do you taste to see if the food's poison?
Yeah, he's great.
Hey, you guys are wearing white. It must be in the stars.
Yuri Geller must be on the premises someplace.
We're gonna operate together.
We just need about six weeks,
and in about six weeks, we could cut the whole album.
I don't know, this is strange to me.
You can come and stay here.
There's a whole wing in this house.
Oh, yeah, stay here?
Really, why are you smiling?
I don't know.
Not only is he a great agent, but he really gives good meaning.
This is a great house, really, everything.
Saunas, jacuzzis, three tennis courts.
You know who the original owners were?
Nelson Eddy, then Legs Diamond.
Then you know who lived here?
Trigger.
Charlie Chaplin.
Hey.
Right before his Un-American thing.
But you guys are still New Yorkers.
Yeah, I love it there.
Well, I used to live there. I used to live there for years.
It's gotten, it's so dirty now.
I'm into garbage. It's my thing.
Well, this is a really nice screening room. It's really nice, Tony.
And there's another thing about New York.
See, if you want to see a movie, you have to stand on line.
It could be freezing, it could be raining.
And here, you're just...
We saw Grand Illusion here last night.
Hey, that's a great film if you're high. It's really funny.
Come and see our bedroom. We did a fantastic thing.
Oh, thanks, ma'am.
Oh, good. Okay.
I'm cool.
That's wonderful.
I mean, you know how they just eat and they watch movies all day?
Yeah, and gradually you get old and die.
You know, it's important to make a little effort once in a while.
You think his girlfriend's beautiful?
Yeah, she's great looking. Great.
Little Ted on the androgynous side, but a dynamite.
Yeah, I forgot my mantra.
That was fun.
I don't think California's bad at all.
It's a drag coming home.
A lot of beautiful women.
It was fun to flirt.
I have to face facts.
I adore Albie, but our relationship doesn't seem to work anymore.
I'll have the usual trouble with Annie in bed tonight
What do I need this?
If only I had the nerve to break up
But it would really hurt him
If only I didn't feel guilty asking Annie to move out
It'd probably wreck her
But I should be honest
Alvy, let's face it
You know, I don't think our relationship is working
I know, a relationship I think is like a shark
You know, it has to constantly move forward or it dies.
And I think what we got on our hands is a dead shark.
Who's catching the riot, sis?
Well, let's see now. If it has my name on it, then I guess it's mine.
Yeah, sure has. You know, you wrote your name in all my books
because you knew this day was going to come.
Well, Albie, you wanted to break up just as much as I do.
No question about it. I think we're doing the mature thing, without any doubt.
Now, look, all the books on death and dying are yours.
and all the poetry books are mine.
It's Denial of Death.
Remember this is the first book that I got you?
Oh, God.
Remember that day?
That's right.
Geez, I feel like there's a great weight off my back.
Hmm.
Oh, thanks, honey.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
I mean, you know, no, no, no.
I mean, I think it's really important for us
to explore new relationships and stuff like that.
There's no question about that
because we've given this, I think,
a more than fair shot, you know.
Yeah, my analyst thinks this move is key for me.
Yeah, and I, you know, I trust it
because my analyst recommended her.
Why should I put you through all my moods and hang-ups anyway?
Right, and you know what the beauty part is?
That we can always come back together again.
Exactly.
There's no problem.
You know, I don't think many couples could handle this.
You know, they could just break up and remain friends.
Hey, this one's mine, this button.
Right.
This one, remember?
I guess these are all yours.
Impeach Eisenhower, impeach Nixon,
impeach Lyndon Johnson, impeach Ronald Reagan.
I miss Annie.
I made a terrible mistake.
She's living in Los Angeles with Tony Lacey.
Oh, yeah? Well, if she is, then to hell with her.
If she likes that lifestyle, let her live there.
He's a jerk, for one thing.
He graduated Harvard?
Yeah. Listen, Harvard makes mistakes, too, you know.
Kissinger taught there.
Don't tell me you're jealous.
Yeah, jealous a little bit, like Madea.
Can I show you something, lady?
I have here, I found this in the apartment, black soap.
She used to wash her face 800 times a day with black soap.
Don't ask me why.
Why don't you go out with other women?
Well, I tried, but it's, you know, it's very depressing.
This always happens to me.
Quick, go get a broom.
What are you making such a big deal about?
They're only lobsters.
You're a grown man. You know how to pick up a lobster.
I'm not myself since I stopped smoking.
Oh, when did you quit smoking?
16 years ago.
What do you mean?
Mean?
You stopped smoking 16 years ago.
Is that what you said?
I don't understand.
Are you joking or what?
Central Park's turning green.
Yeah, I saw that lunatic
that we used to see with the pinwheel hat and the roller skates.
Listen, I want you to come back here.
Well, then I'm going to come out there and get you.
What do you mean, where am I? Where do you think I am?
I'm at the Los Angeles airport. I flew in.
Well, I flew in to see you.
Hey, listen, can we not debate this on the telephone?
because I feel that I got a temperature
and I'm getting my chronic Los Angeles nausea ready.
I don't feel so good.
Well, wherever you want to meet, I don't care.
I'll drive in. I rented a car.
I'm driving.
What is that, such a miracle?
I'm driving myself.
I'm gonna have the alfalfa sprouts and a plate of mashed yeast.
Hi.
You look very pretty.
Oh, no, I just lost a little weight, that's all.
Well, you look nice.
I've been thinking about it, and I think that we should get married.
Oh, Albie, come on.
What, you want to live out here or what do you think?
It's like living in munchkin land.
What do you mean? I mean, it's perfectly fine out here.
I mean, Tony's very nice, and, uh, well, I meet people,
and I go to parties, and we play tennis.
I mean, that's a very big step for me, you know?
I mean, I'm able to enjoy people more.
So what do you want?
You're not gonna come back to New York?
What's so great about New York?
I mean, it's a dying city.
You read Death in Venice.
Hey, you didn't read Death in Venice
till I bought it for you.
That's right, that's right.
You only gave me books with the word death in the title.
That's right, because it's an important issue.
Alvy, you're incapable of enjoying life, you know that?
I mean, you're like New York City.
You're just this person. You're like this island unto yourself.
I can't enjoy anything unless I... unless everybody is.
You know, if one guy is starving someplace, that's...
You know, I... I put a crimp in my evening.
So you want to get married or what?
No. We're friends.
I want to remain friends.
Okay. Check, please. Can I...
You're mad, aren't you?
Yes, of course I'm mad, because you love me. I know that.
Albie, I can't say that that's true at this point in my life.
I really just can't say that that's true.
I mean, you know how wonderful you are.
I mean, you know... You're the reason that I got out of my room
and that I was able to sing and, you know,
get more in touch with my feelings and all that crap.
Anyway, look, I don't want... Listen, listen, listen.
Listen, um...
So what are you up to, anyway, huh?
The usual. You know, I'm trying to write.
I'm working on a play.
So what are you saying? That you're not coming back to New York with me?
No, look...
I gotta go.
What do you mean? I flew 3,000 miles to see you.
I'm late. Air miles, you know?
I mean, you know what that does to my stomach?
You must know it's a hectic time for Tony. The Grammys are tonight.
The what?
The Grammys. He's got a lot of records up for awards.
Really? They give awards for that kind of music? I thought just earplugs.
Just forget it, Albie, okay? Let's just forget the conversation.
They give awards. They do nothing but give out awards. I can't believe it.
Greatest, greatest fascist dictator, Adolf Hitler.
I know what you're going to say.
I'm not a great driver.
You know, I have some problems with...
Sir, your license, please.
Just don't get angry or anything,
Because I have my license here.
You know, it's a rented car, and I...
Don't give me your license.
Dory, just pick up the license.
Oh, pick up the license. You have to ask nicely,
because I've had an extremely rough day.
You know, my girlfriend...
Just give me the license, please.
Since you put it that way, it's hard for me to refuse.
I have a terrific problem with authority, you know.
It's not your fault. Don't take it personal.
What's wrong, fellas?
Keep in touch.
Imagine my surprise when I got your call, Max.
Yeah, I had the feeling that I got you at a bad moment.
You know, I heard high-pitched squealing.
Twins, Max.
16-year-old.
Can you imagine the mathematical possibilities of that?
You're an actor, Max. You should be doing Shakespeare in the Park.
Oh, I did Shakespeare in the Park, Max. I got mugged.
I was playing Richard II and two guys with leather jackets stole my leotard.
Max, are we driving through plutonium?
Keeps out the alpha rays, Max.
You don't get old.
You're a thinking person.
How can you choose this lifestyle?
What is so incredibly great about New York?
It's a dying city.
You read Death in Venice.
You didn't read Death in Venice till I gave it to you.
Well, you only give me books with the word death in the title.
It's an important issue.
Artie, you are totally incapable of enjoying life.
You're like New York.
You're an island.
Okay.
If that's all that we've been through together means to you,
I guess it's better if we just said goodbye, once and for all.
You know what's funny?
After all the serious talks and passionate moments,
that it ends here, in a health food restaurant on Sunset Boulevard.
Goodbye, Sally.
Wait.
I'm gonna go with you.
I love you.
What do you want? It was my first play.
You know how you're always trying to get things to come out perfect in art
because it's real difficult in life.
Interestingly, however, I did run into Annie again.
It was on the Upper West Side of Manhattan.
She had moved back to New York.
She was living in Soho with some guy.
And when I met her, she was, of all things,
dragging him in to see The Sorrow and the Pity,
which I counted as a personal triumph.
And Annie and I, we had lunch sometime after that
and just kicked around old times.
Just to have my arms around you
Still the thrill
That it was the day I found you seems like old times.
Dinner dates and flowers
Oh, Tom
After that, it got pretty late, and we both had to go,
but it was great seeing Annie again.
I realized what a terrific person she was
and how much fun it was just knowing her.
And I thought of that old joke, you know,
this guy goes to a psychiatrist and says,
Doc, my brother's crazy.
He thinks he's a chicken.
And the doctor says, well, why don't you turn him in?
And the guy says, I would, but I need the eggs.
Well, I guess that's pretty much now how I feel about relationships.
You know, they're totally irrational and crazy and absurd.
But I guess we keep going through it because most of us need the eggs.
Oh, oh, oh.
Thank you.
you
You